<optimization_record_list>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
NONE
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Power Optimization Advisor
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
This advisor gives recommendations on how to reduce design power consumption. 
</recommendation_description>
<description>

</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="">
	NA
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA 
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
GEN
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
General Recommendations
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The following recommendations are general recommendations for any design. Double-click a category to view the recommendations for that category.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
NA
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	NONE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
HOWTO
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
How to use the Power Optimization Advisor
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Implement the recommendations in the Power Optimization Advisor to optimize the power usage of your design. 
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Altera recommends evaluating the power optimizations in Stage 1 before moving on to Stage 2. 
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	0
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	0
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the recommendations provided by the Power Optimization Advisor to make project or individual settings and assignments, or make design changes to optimize the power usage in your design.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="0">
	NONE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
MOREINFO
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Get more information
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can use the Support section of the Altera web site or Quartus II Help to obtain more information on the specific recommendations and Quartus II settings and assignments in the Power Optimization Advisor.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can find many of the recommendations in the Power Optimization Advisor in the Design Optimization for Altera Devices chapter of the Quartus II Handbook and in the low-power design for Stratix II and Cyclone II application note. You can also get help on the specific settings and assignments described in the Power Optimization Advisor by using Quartus II Help.  For the Stratix III device family, see also Application Note AN437.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	 N/A
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	For more information, use the Design Optimization for Altera Devices chapter of the Quartus II Handbook, Application Note 401 on low-power design for Stratix II and Cyclone II devices, or Quartus II Help.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	GEN
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
REV
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Create a revision
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Create a revision before making the recommended project and individual settings and assignments and design changes.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can create a revision before implementing the recommendations in the Power Optimization Advisor, and then compare the revisions after performing a compilation to view the results.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus\common\help\save.chm::/rev/rev_view_rev.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	 N/A
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Create a revision using the Revisions dialog box (Project Menu), make the recommended changes, perform a compilation, and then view the results of the compilation using the Compare Revisions dialog box (Project menu).
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	REV
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="3">
	GEN
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
SMART_COMPILE
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use smart compilation
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Turn on smart compilation to minimize compilation time.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
During a recompilation after a smart compilation, the Compiler determines which Compiler modules are required to process the current design based on the changes made to the design since the smart compilation, and then skips any modules that are not required. Refer to Use Smart Compilation in the Quartus II Help using the link below.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus\common\help\quartus.chm::/comp.chm::/comp/comp_tab_mode.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	0
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Turn on Use smart compilation in the Compilation Process page of the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu).
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_COMPILATION
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="SMART_RECOMPILE">
		ON
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="4">
	GEN
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
PU_STAGE1
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Stage 1
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The following are recommendations for Stage 1. Altera recommends implementing the recommendations in Stage 1 before the recommendations in Stage 2.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
NA
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	NONE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
PU_STAGE2
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Stage 2
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The following are recommendations for Stage 2. Altera recommends implementing the recommendations in Stage 2 after the recommendations in Stage 1. Stage 2 recommendations generally involve design changes, rather than CAD settings changes.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
NA
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="3">
	NONE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
REAL_TIMING_CONSTRAINTS
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Set Realistic Timing Constraints
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Set realistic timing constraints for your design.  Constrain all clocks as required for correct operation of the design.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Realistic timing constraints are required for two reasons.  First, the Quartus II PowerPlay power analysis and optimization flows use clock Fmax constraints to derive toggle rates for signals in your design when simulation data is not available.  Overconstraining a clock, i.e. providing an unrealistically high Fmax constraint for a clock, will result in an overprediction of toggle rates for those nodes, which will result in an overprediction of dynamic power.  Second, when the Fitter optimizes it must trade off timing performance goals against power reduction goals while also trying to limit compile time.  Providing realistic clock constraints allows the Fitter to balance those goals appropriately, i.e. achieve timing with some margin, and then secondarily reduce power.  If clocks are unrealistically overconstrained, then the Fitter will spend effort optimizing timing while it could have worked on reducing power or compile time.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus\common\help\reference.chm::/glossary/def_time_require.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	0
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Quartus II has two timing analyzers: the TimeQuest Timing Analyzer, and the Classic Timing Analyzer.  First decide which timing analyzer you want to use for timing optimization and verification of your design.  Each timing analyzer has its own way of specifying the timing constraints.  Consult the Timing Optimization Advisor for more guidance.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_TIMING
	</action_link>
	<action_link>
	TWIZ
	</action_link>
	<action_link>
	AE_TIMING
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="0">
	PU_STAGE1
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
POWER_ANALYZE
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Run the PowerPlay Power Analyzer
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Run the PowerPlay Power Analyzer to determine your design power, and to see where power is dissipated in your design.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Run the PowerPlay Power Analyzer both to determine how much power your design dissipates, and to determine what portions of the design are dissipating the most power, and hence are the most likely candidates for optimization. To obtain the most accurate power estimates, you should simulate your design at the gate-level, with glitch filtering enabled, using a testbench that exercises the typical operation of the design. You can use either the Quartus II simulator or any 3rd party simulator that can generate a Verilog Change Dump (VCD) file. An accurate PowerPlay analysis of your design is also necessary for some optimization tools, such as the Design Space Explorer and PowerPlay Power Optimization during fitting to be most effective.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii53013.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	You can run the PowerPlay Power Analyzer from the Start line on the Processing menu. You should use the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu) to set the PowerPlay Power Analyzer to use simulation-based data for toggle rates, either from a Signal Activity (SAF) file generated by the Quartus II simulator or from a Verilog Change Dump (VCD) file generated by the Quartus II simulator or a 3rd party simulator. You should also enable glitch filtering during simulation and glitch filtering when a VCD file is read by the Power Analyzer.  This will filter out spurious transitions that are too fast for the FPGA logic and routing to respond, since such glitches during simulation will result in a power over-estimation if they are not filtered. If you are using a 3rd party VHDL simulator, you should enable mapping of illegal VHDL characters to ensure all signals have valid names, so their toggle rates can be retrieved from the VCD file by the Quartus II software.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_POWER_ANALYZER
	</action_link>
	<action_link>
	SETD_SIM_POWER
	</action_link>
	<action_link>
	SETD_EDA_SIM
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="POWER_VCD_FILTER_GLITCHES">
		ON
		</acf_variable>
		<acf_variable name="SIMULATOR_GENERATE_SIGNAL_ACTIVITY_FILE">
		ON
		</acf_variable>
		<acf_variable name="SIMULATION_WITH_GLITCH_FILTERING">
		ON
		</acf_variable>
		<acf_variable name="EDA_MAP_ILLEGAL_CHARACTERS">
		ON
		</acf_variable>
		<acf_variable name="EDA_ENABLE_GLITCH_FILTERING">
		ON
		</acf_variable>
		<acf_variable name="EDA_WRITE_NODES_FOR_POWER_ESTIMATION">
		ALL_NODES
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	PU_STAGE1
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DEVICE_SELECT
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Appropriate Device Family
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Choose a device family with the dynamic and static power characteristics best suited to your application.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Different device families have different power dissipation characteristics.  In general, devices manufactured in more recent process technologies tend to have lower overall power.  For example, a Stratix III device tends to dissipate less power than a Stratix II device with a similar density.  Also, a device from a low cost family tends to dissipate less power than a device with similar density from the high performance family in the same process technology.  For example, both Cyclone II and Stratix II are manufactured in a 90nm process technology, but generally speaking a Cyclone II device tends to dissipate less power than a similarly sized Stratix II device.  Another consideration is the balance between static power and dynamic power.  If signals in your design have a relatively high average toggle rate, then its total power will be dominated by I/O and core dynamic power.  In that case, choose a device manufactured on a more recent process technology, and use a lower cost device if possible.  If signals in your design have a very low average toggle rate, then total power will be dominated by static power.  In that case, choose a device with lower static power.  For example, MAX II devices have very low static power, in particular the MAX II G and MAX II Z devices.  Finally, HardCopy II structured ASICs allow migration of Stratix II designs to the HardCopy II structured ASIC, which leads to a large reduction in both static and dynamic power.  Use the PowerPlay Power Analyzer within the Quartus II software or the PowerPlay Early Power Estimator available at www.altera.com to evaluate the power characteristics of various device families for your design.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/support/devices/estimator/pow-powerplay.html
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Select a device family whose power characteristics are well suited to your application from the Device page of the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu).
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_DEVICE
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	PU_STAGE1
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
USE_LOWER_VOLTAGE
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Select a Low Core Voltage
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Select a low core voltage for Stratix III devices.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Stratix III devices in the 4L speed grade allow you to select the core voltage.  Lowering the core voltage reduces static power by approximately 25 percent and core dynamic power by approximately 33 percent.  Lowering the core voltage also increases delay for core resources.  The performance of peripheral resources such as IO, PLL, and Serdes blocks is unaffected. Compile time might increase because the Fitter may be forced to work harder to meet your design's timing requirements.  Please refer to the Stratix III data sheet for the supported voltages for the VCCL power rail.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus\common\help\optimize.chm::/pwr/pwr_tab_pppa_operating_conditions-voltage.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	-1
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Select a Stratix III device in the 4L speed grade from the Device page of the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu).  Then select the Low Voltage setting for the Core Supply Voltage option in the Operating Settings and Conditions, Voltage page of the Settings dialog box.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_DEVICE
	</action_link>
	<action_link>
	SETD_VOLTAGE
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NOMINAL_CORE_SUPPLY_VOLTAGE">
		0.9v
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIII
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="3">
	PU_STAGE1
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DEVICE_MAXIIZ_MAXIIG
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
MAX II Z Device or MAX II G Device
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Use a MAX II Z device or MAX II G device for lower power.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
MAX II Z and G devices are powered directly from a 1.8V supply, while other MAX II devices use an on-chip voltage regulator to reduce a 2.5V or 3.3V supply to 1.8V on chip. Consequently MAX II Z and G devices have significantly lower dynamic and static power than other MAX II devices.  Additionally, MAX II Z devices are manufactured in an optimized process to achieve extremely low static power, in the micro-Watt range.  Select a MAX II Z device when possible, and otherwise select a MAX II G device when possible.
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Select MAX II Z or MAX II G device from the Device page of the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu).
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_DEVICE
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="DEVICE">
		EPM240ZM100C6|EPM240ZM100C7|EPM240ZM68C6|EPM240ZM68C7|EPM570ZM100C6|EPM570ZM100C7|EPM570ZM144C6|EPM570ZM144C7|EPM570ZM256C6|EPM570ZM256C7|EPM240GF100C5|EPM240GF100I5|EPM240GM100C5|EPM240GM100I5|EPM240GT100C3|EPM240GT100C4|EPM240GT100C5|EPM240GT100I5|EPM570GF100C5|EPM570GF100I5|EPM570GF256C3|EPM570GF256C4|EPM570GF256C5|EPM570GF256I5|EPM570GM100C5|EPM570GM100I5|EPM570GM256C5|EPM570GM256I5|EPM570GT100C3|EPM570GT100C4|EPM570GT100C5|EPM570GT100I5|EPM570GT144C3|EPM570GT144C4|EPM570GT144C5|EPM570GT144I5|EPM1270GF256C3|EPM1270GF256C4|EPM1270GF256C5|EPM1270GF256I5|EPM1270GM256C5|EPM1270GM256I5|EPM1270GT144C3|EPM1270GT144C4|EPM1270GT144C5|EPM1270GT144I5|EPM2210GF256C3|EPM2210GF256C4|EPM2210GF256C5|EPM2210GF256I5|EPM2210GF324C3|EPM2210GF324C4|EPM2210GF324C5|EPM2210GF324I5
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	MAXII
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="4">
	PU_STAGE1
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DYNAMIC_POWER
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Dynamic Power
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The following recommendations list methods to reduce dynamic power. Dynamic power is the portion of operating power that increases linearly with operating frequency.
</recommendation_description>
<description>

</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="6">
	PU_STAGE1
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA 
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
STATIC_POWER
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Static Power
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The following recommendations can reduce static power dissipation. Static power is the frequency independent power dissipated by a design, even when the design clocks are stopped.
</recommendation_description>
<description>

</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="7">
	PU_STAGE1
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DSE_POWER
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Design Space Explorer
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Run the Design Space Explorer (DSE) tcl script in quartus/common/tcl/apps/dse/dse.tcl, and choose the optimize for power mode. 
</recommendation_description>
<description>
DSE will automatically compile your design with various Quartus settings, and return Quartus compile settings that achieve the lowest power while meeting your design timing requirements.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus\common\help\optimize.chm::/dse/dse_about_dse.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	0
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	-1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Start the Design Space Explorer, and select the Search for Lowest Power mode.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	DSE
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	DYNAMIC_POWER
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
PDC_SYNTHESIS
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Power-Driven Synthesis
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Set PowerPlay Power Optimization during synthesis to Extra Effort.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Extra effort power-driven synthesis will choose logic and RAM implementations which minimize design dynamic power.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus\common\help\optimize.chm::/pwr/pwr_pro_power_opt_compilation.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	-1
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	-1
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	0
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Set PowerPlay Power Optimization during synthesis to Extra Effort
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_ANALYSIS_SYNTHESIS
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="OPTIMIZE_POWER_DURING_SYNTHESIS">
		EXTRA EFFORT
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ACF
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	DYNAMIC_POWER
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
PDC_FITTING
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Power-Driven Fitting
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Set PowerPlay Power Optimization during fitting to Extra Effort.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Extra effort power-driven fitting will minimize the power required by your design by ensuring rapidly toggling signals use minimal routing, and use the most power-efficient logic, RAM and DSP block modes. Extra effort power-driven fitting may reduce the achievable timing performance of your design.  To optimize for power most effectively, power-driven fitting requires information about the toggle rate of each signal in your design. The more accurate this toggle rate information is, the better the results from power-driven fitting. The recommended flow for power-driven fitting is: (1) compile your design; (2) perform a gate-level simulation with glitch filtering to generate a VCD or SAF file; (3) use the Power Analyzer to read in the VCD file and convert it to a SAF file (you can skip this step if you generated a SAF file directly from the Quartus II simulator in step #2); (4) enter the name of the SAF file in the SAF file dialog box in the PowerPlay Power Analyzer settings; and (5) recompile your design with PowerPlay Power Optimization during fitting set to Extra Effort. Steps 1 through 3 can optionally be replaced by performing an RTL-level simulation to generate a SAF file. However, the signal toggle rate data may not be as accurate as that produced by a gate-level simulation, and this may reduce optimization quality.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus\common\help\optimize.chm::/pwr/pwr_pro_power_opt_compilation.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	-1
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	-1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Set PowerPlay Power Optimization during fitting to Extra Effort
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_FITTER
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="OPTIMIZE_POWER_DURING_FITTING">
		EXTRA EFFORT
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ACF
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	DYNAMIC_POWER
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
AREA_DRIVEN_SYNTH
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Minimum Area Synthesis
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Set your synthesis tool to optimize area. 
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Reducing the resource usage of your design generally reduces dynamic power by reducing the number of toggling blocks and the amount of toggling routing. As well, reducing resource use can allow use of a smaller device, which reduces static power.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus\common\help\logicops.chm::/logicops/def_optimization_technique.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	-1
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	1
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Set the synthesis optimization style to Area, and make appropriate settings in any 3rd party synthesis tool you are using.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_ANALYSIS_SYNTHESIS
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="FAMILY_group:OPTIMIZATION_TECHNIQUE">
		AREA
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="3">
	DYNAMIC_POWER
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
WYSIWYG_REMAP
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
WYSIWYG primitive remapping
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Enable WYSIWYG primitive resynthesis in Quartus II software.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
This option is only useful if you are using a third-party synthesis tool such as Synplify or Precision Synthesis. In that case, this option allows Quartus II software to further optimize the portions of the design synthesized with a third-party tool. For the best power reduction, you should also set the Logic Synthesis Style to Area, and set PowerPlay power optimization during synthesis to Extra Effort.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	0
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	1
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	-1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Turn WYSIWYG remapping on in the Analysis &amp; Synthesis Settings page of the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu).
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_SYNTHESIS_NETLIST
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="ADV_NETLIST_OPT_SYNTH_WYSIWYG_REMAP">
		ON
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ACF
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="4">
	DYNAMIC_POWER
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DEDICATED_RESOURCE_DSP
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use DSP Blocks
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Use DSP blocks for multiply, multiply accumulate and complex multiplication functions rather than implementing these functions in logic cells. 
</recommendation_description>
<description>
The altmult_accum megafunction can be used to instantiate DSP blocks; some DSP block functions can also be inferred from Hardware Description Language descriptions. Entire Finite Impulse Response (FIR) filters can also be implemented with little general routing or logic using DSP blocks available in Stratix class and Arria GX devices.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	1
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	1
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the MegaWizard Plug-In Manager (Tools menu) or appropriately coded Hardware Description Language to implement a function in a DSP block.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIX
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXGX
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	CYCLONEII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	HARDCOPYII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIIGX
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ARRIAGX
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	CYCLONEIII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIV
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
2
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	PU_STAGE2
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DEDICATED_RESOURCE_RAM
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use RAM Blocks
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Use the M512, M4K, M9K, M144K and M-RAM blocks, instead of logic cell registers to implement RAMs and medium to large shift registers. 
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Use the Memory Compiler MegaWizards to implement RAM and ROM blocks, and leave the type and depth of RAM unspecified.  Extra Effort PowerPlay Power Optimization during synthesis will choose the appropriate RAM type and depth to minimize power. Shift registers whose (width x depth) is greater than approximately 25 bits are more power-efficiently implemented with a RAM-based FIFO, using the altshift_taps megafunction. Both RAM blocks and RAM-based shift registers will also be automatically inferred from appropriately-coded HDL by most synthesis tools.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	1
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	1
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the MegaWizard Plug-In Manager (Tools menu) or appropriately coded Hardware Description Language to implement a function in a RAM block.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="MAXII">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX7000A">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX7000B">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX7000AE">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX7000S">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX3000A">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="FLEX6000">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
2
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="3">
	PU_STAGE2
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DYN_USE_ENABLES_ON_RAMS
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Shut Down RAM Blocks
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Use the clock enable, read enable and write enable ports on RAM blocks to shut them down during cycles in which the RAM is not read or written.  If your design does not depend on a specific read result when reading and writing the same address, then specify "don't care" for the read-during-write parameter in the RAM Megawizard.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Most energy in dedicated RAM blocks is dissipated whenever the RAM is accessed for a read or write cycle, even with the address, write data and read data is not changing from cycle to cycle. Consequently on cycles where a RAM does not need to be read or written, it is more power efficient to specify a clock enable in the altsyncram or other megafunction so that the RAM is not activated, rather than simply reading the RAM and ignoring the output data. Specifying clock enables directly in the megafunctions is best. Specifying read and/or write enables on the altsyncram or other megafunction is also useful, as PowerPlay Power Optimization during synthesis will convert these signals to clock enables on the RAM as appropriate.  For some RAM modes in Cyclone III and Stratix III, specifying "don't care" for the read-during-write parameter of the RAM Megawizard allows Quartus to disable useless reads when writing.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	0
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	0
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the MegaWizard Plug-In Manager (Tools menu) to create read, write and clock enables on RAM blocks.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="MAXII">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX7000A">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX7000B">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX7000AE">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX7000S">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="MAX3000A">
	ALL
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="FLEX6000">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
2
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="4">
	PU_STAGE2
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DYN_USE_ENABLES_ON_LOGIC
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Clock Enables on Logic
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Whenever logic is not used on a significant fraction of clock cycles, specify a clock enable in your design HDL, schematic or megafunction instantiations so that the appropriate registers are shut down on these cycles. 
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Using a clock enable to shut down registers reduces power even when the data input to those registers is not changing on a given clock cycle, since the portion of a clock inside the LAB or DSP block is shut down by the enable, and hence clock power is reduced by clock enables.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	0
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	0
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Write your Hardware Description Language (or other design entry format) code such that clock enables are used whenever appropriate on registers.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
2
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="5">
	PU_STAGE2
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DYN_PIPELINE
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Pipeline Logic to Reduce Glitching
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Add pipeline registers to combinational logic paths that are glitching (toggling several times per clock cycle) to reduce signal toggling, and hence dynamic power. 
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Circuits that make heavy use of xor functions (e.g. cyclic redundancy check, multiplies) tend to glitch significantly when cascaded. Inserting pipeline registers before, after, or in the middle of such logic can reduce glitching and hence power. Examine the toggle rate data from the PowerPlay Power Analyzer Report to find rapidly toggling signals that are likely candidates for glitch reduction via pipelining.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	1
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	-1
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	0
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Add pipeline registers to your design as appropriate.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
3
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="6">
	PU_STAGE2
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
DYN_CLK_CTRL
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Stop Clock When Idle
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Use the altclkctrl megafunction to power-down a clock domain when it is idle. 
</recommendation_description>
<description>
If an entire clock domain is idle for a period of time, it is most power efficient to shut the clock down. This eliminates power consumed to charge and discharge the clock tree, and ensures logic on this clock domain does not toggle. Use the altclkctrl megafunction to safely insert a clock shutdown block in your design.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	0
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	0
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the MegaWizard Plug-In Manager (Tools menu) to create altclkctrl functions for clock domains which you wish to shut down.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	CYCLONEII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	HARDCOPYII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIIGX
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ARRIAGX
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	CYCLONEIII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIV
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
3
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="7">
	PU_STAGE2
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
STATIC_INDUSTRIAL_STRATIXII
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Industrial Stratix II Device
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Target a Stratix II industrial device if you plan to run at high junction temperatures, and lower static power is important in your application.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Stratix II industrial devices have lower core (Vccint) static power than commercial devices at high junction temperatures. 
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Select an industrial Stratix II device from the Device page of the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu). Industrial devices contain an "I" near the end of the part code.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_DEVICE
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="DEVICE">
		EP2S130F1020I4|EP2S130F1508I4|EP2S15F484I4|EP2S15F672I4|EP2S180F1020I4|EP2S180F1508I4|EP2S30F484I4|EP2S30F484I4|EP2S30F672I4|EP2S60F1020I4|EP2S60F484I4|EP2S60F672I4|EP2S90F1020I4|EP2S90F1508I4
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXII
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	STATIC_POWER
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
APPROPRIATE_IO
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Appropriate I/O Standards
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Choose appropriate I/O standards to minimize design power.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Choosing appropriate I/O standards can significantly reduce design power. To reduce power, use a low-voltage I/O standard (most important) and the lowest drive strength that will meet your speed requirements. For lower frequency applications or applications where I/Os are idle most of the time, I/O standards which are not resistively terminated, such as LVTTL, LVCMOS and PCI have the lowest total power, since they have very low static power. However, as I/O toggle rates increase these I/O standards eventually dissipate more power than resistively terminated standards such as SSTL, HSTL and LVDS, as the unterminated I/O standards generally have higher dynamic power. Use the PowerPlay Power Analyzer to analyze different I/O configurations and choose the lowest power option for your system.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the Assignment Editor (Assignments menu) and the I/O Standard Option to set appropriate I/O standards on your design I/Os.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	AE
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	PU_STAGE2
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
USE_ONLY_LOW_SPEED_LABS
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use Only Low Power LABs
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Set all LABs to Low Power mode in Stratix III and Stratix IV devices
</recommendation_description>
<description>
The Stratix III and Stratix IV device families feature Programmable Power Technology, an advanced architecture that enables a smooth tradeoff between speed and power.  The primary benefit of Programmable Power Technology is to reduce static power, with a secondary benefit being a small reduction in dynamic power.  If your design meets timing with significant margin, then by default almost all LAB tiles will be set automatically to operate in Low Power mode.  You may override the Fitter optimization algorithm and force it instead to set all LAB tiles to operate in Low Power mode.  If your design did not meet timing by a significant margin, then your design will likely fail timing with this option and you may have to use other techniques to close timing. For more information on Programmable Power Technology, see the online help topic About Power Estimation and Analysis, Factors Affecting Power Consumption, Device Selection.  To optimize the timing of your design, see the Timing Optimization Advisor.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52016.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	-1
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Select the Minimize Power Only setting for the Programmable Power Technology Optimization option in the More Fitter Settings page under the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu).
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_FITTER
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="PROGRAMMABLE_POWER_TECHNOLOGY_SETTING">
		MINIMIZE_POWER_ONLY
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIV
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="8">
	PU_STAGE2
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
SETTING
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
STATIC_SMALLER_DEVICE
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Small Device
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Use the smallest device which can fit your design.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Within each device family, smaller devices contain fewer transistors and consequently have lower static power. Hence targeting the smallest device in a family which can fit your design will reduce static power. See the Resource Optimization Advisor for guidelines on how to fit more logic into a smaller device.
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Select the smallest device which can fit your design from the Device page of the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu). 
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_DEVICE
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	STATIC_POWER
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
STATIC_LOW_TEMP
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Reduce Junction Temperature
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Use a better cooling solution (use a heat sink, and/or add airflow to the system) or reduce dynamic or I/O power to reduce the junction temperature. This will result in lower device static power.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Static power drawn from the Vccint supply increases with junction temperature. A better cooling solution or a reduction in dynamic or I/O power dissipation will reduce junction temperature, which will reduce static power.
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Open the Operating Settings and Conditions, Temperature page of the Settings dialog box to change your cooling solution.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_POWER_OPERATING_CONDITION
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	CYCLONEII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	HARDCOPYII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIIGX
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ARRIAGX
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	CYCLONEIII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIV
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
2
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="4">
	STATIC_POWER
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
STATIC_USE_FASTER_SPEED_GRADE
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Select a Faster Speed Grade Device
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
For Stratix III and Stratix IV devices, select a faster speed grade.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
The Stratix III and Stratix IV device families feature Programmable Power Technology, an advanced architecture that enables a smooth tradeoff between speed and power.  The Fitter automatically sets most core tiles to Low Power mode, and only timing critical LAB tiles will be set to High Speed mode.  When you select a faster speed grade, the Fitter can achieve more timing margin, and therefore set more LAB tiles to Low Power mode.  Both static and dynamic power are reduced when fewer tiles are set to High Speed mode.  Note that rather than selecting a faster speed grade, if you can meet timing with a lower core voltage then your design will consume less power by using the lower core voltage.  See the "Select a Low Core Voltage" recommendation elsewhere in this advisor.  For more information on Programmable Power Technology, see the online help topic About Power Estimation and Analysis, Factors Affecting Power Consumption, Device Selection.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus\common\help\optimize.chm::/pwr/pwr_about_pwr.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	1
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	0
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	1
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	From the Device page on the Settings dialog box (Assignments menu), select the fastest speed grade available for the Stratix III device.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_DEVICE
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIII
	</device_family>
	<device_family exclude="">
	STRATIXIV
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>

</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="5">
	STATIC_POWER
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>
</optimization_record_list>
