<optimization_record_list>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
NONE
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Tips &amp; Tricks
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Learn about some tips and tricks you can use in the Quartus II Software. You can open this tool from the Help menu.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
NA
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	NA
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	NA
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	NA
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="">
	NA
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
INFO
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
What's New in this Release
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Find out what is new in this release of the Quartus II software.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
The Online Help includes a list of new and changed features in each release of the software.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/gl_new_features.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Open the What's New page in the Quartus II Online Help.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	NONE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
FEATURES
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Quartus II Features
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You may want to try out these features in the Quartus II software.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
NA
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	NONE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
F1
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Detach windows from the frame in the Quartus II software
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can detach most windows from the frame in the Quartus II software to give you more flexibility and to take advantage of systems with multiple monitors.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Many of the windows including the Editors, the Pin Planner, the Chip Planner, and many other windows are now detachable. 
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the Detach Window command on the Window menu, or the toolbar button to detach a window so it floats outside the main window of the Quartus II software.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	FEATURES
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
F2
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Get advice on optimizing your design and the features of the Quartus II software
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can use the Quartus II Advisors to get advice on how to improve the timing, resource usage, and power usage in your design.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
The Timing Optimization Advisor, Resource Optimization Advisor, and Power Optimization Advisor use current project information and settings to make recommendations of project settings and assignments, individual entity assignments, and design changes for optimizing a project for power, resource usage, or timing.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/report.chm::/oaw/oaw_view_using_oaw.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the Advisors on the Tools menu to get  recommendations based on your design.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	FEATURES
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
F3
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Get an Early Timing Estimate
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can get an early timing estimate without running a full compilation.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can use the Start Early Timing Estimate command on the Processing menu to get a full timing report based on estimated delays for the design. This command can run the Fitter up to ten times faster than a full fit and produces estimated delays within 20% of what a full compilation can achieve.
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the Start Early Timing Estimate command on the Processing menu to run an early timing estimate. You can specify settings for the early timing estimate in the Settings dialog box when a project is open.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_EARLY_TIMING_ESTIMATE
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="3">
	FEATURES
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
F4
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use Incremental Compilation
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The incremental compilation feature of the Quartus II software allows you to separately compile isolated portions, or partitions, of the design and reduces compilation time and run-time memory consumption by recompiling only the design partitions that have changed. Incremental compilation is a useful development tool if you have a large project and want to focus on developing isolated segments of it, while preserving performance in other portions of the project. Incremental compilation is also useful for achieving timing closure. You can use this feature to apply optimization techniques, such as physical synthesis, to specific design partitions that do not meet timing goals while leaving other partitions untouched.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Incremental compilation supports both top-down and bottom-up design flows. In the top-down design flow, a single designer compiles and optimizes the top-level design as a whole. The bottom-up design flow allows you to create a top-level design that instantiates any number of lower-level projects as design partitions. You can then design and optimize each partition as an independent Quartus II project and later integrate it into the top-level design with Quartus II export and import features, which permits team-based development. You should consider the size and scope of a project and available resources when you choose the design flow methodology. Both design flows benefit designers who want to reduce compilation, design, and debugging times, and preserve performance for their hierarchical designs.
</description>
<more_info_link>
comp.chm::/increment/comp_view_qid.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	In the Incremental Compilation Advisor on the Tools menu, You can follow the steps to help you set your design up for Incremental Compilation.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	INCREMENTAL_COMPILATION_ADVISOR
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="4">
	FEATURES
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
F5
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use SignalProbe to quickly pull out internal signals to pins
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The SignalProbe feature allows you to route user-specified signals to output pins without affecting the existing fitting in a design. You can investigate internal device signals without performing a full compilation with the SignalProbe feature.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
After performing a full compilation you can use the SignalProbe Pins command on the Tools menu to configure internal signals to pins to help analyze your design. After setting up the signals you want routed to pins you can quickly route the internal signals to external pins with the Start SignalProbe Compilation command on the Processing menu.
</description>
<more_info_link>
program.chm::/sipro/comp_intro_signalprobe.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To configure internal signals to pins, open the SignalProbe Pins dialog box on the Tools menu. Then click Start SignalProbe Compilation on the Processing menu to have the fitter connect the signals to external pins.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SIGNAL_PROBE_PINS_DLG
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="5">
	FEATURES
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
F5
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use the PowerPlay Power Analyzer to check for power usage
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The Quartus II software provides PowerPlay power estimation and analysis tools that allow you to estimate device power consumption and heat dissipation from early design concept through design implementation.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Early in your design cycle, you can use PowerPlay Early Power Estimator on the Project menu to create spreadsheets that provide preliminary power consumption and heat dissipation estimates for supported device families. To calculate the estimates, you enter information about environmental conditions and the number of device resources (such as clocks, RAM blocks, and DSP blocks) that you expect to use in your design. When your design is partially complete, you can generate a PowerPlay Early Power Estimator file in the Quartus II software to provide the Early Power Estimator with your design's device resource profile. Late in your design cycle, you can use the PowerPlay Power Analyzer on the Processing menu in the Quartus II software to provide the most accurate estimate of device power consumption and heat dissipation.
</description>
<more_info_link>
optimize.chm::/pwr/pwr_about_pwr.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Use the Generate PowerPlay Early Power Estimator File command on the Project menu to create a spreadsheet that helps you estimate your power usage. Use the Start PowerPlay Power Analyzer command on the Processing menu to generate power estimates after you have created your design. You can set options for the PowerPlay Power Analyzer in the Settings dialog box when a project is open.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_POWER_ANALYZER
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="5">
	FEATURES
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
F6
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use Netlist Viewers to view your design schematic
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The Netlist Viewers consist of the RTL Viewer, the State Machine Viewer, and the Technology Map Viewer. All of these viewers provide a schematic view and have debugging features for performing trace and debug operations on your HDL designs.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
The RTL Viewer allows you to view the schematic of the design netlist after analysis and elaboration. You can use the RTL Viewer options to change the optimization settings to create a variation of the final schematic display.  You can use the  Technology Map Viewer to view a low-level, technology-specific schematic of the design netlist after fitting or after analysis and synthesis. You can use the State Machine Viewer to provide a graphical representation of the states and their related transitions, as well as a state transition table that displays the condition equation for each of the state transitions.
</description>
<more_info_link>
verify.chm::/rtl/rtl_view.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	You open the Netlist Viewers by pointing to Netlist Viewers on the Tools menu, and then clicking RTL Viewer, Technology Map Viewer, or State Machine Viewer. In order to open the RTL Viewer, you must perform at least Analysis &amp; Elaboration on the design. In order to open the Technology Map Viewer, you must perform at least Analysis &amp; Synthesis on the design to view the post-mapping view of the netlist. In order to view the post-fitting view of the netlist, you must perform a full compilation.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="7">
	FEATURES
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
SOFTWARE
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Software Options
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Software options determine the behavior of the Quartus II software across all projects.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
NA
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="3">
	NONE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S1
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Generate Compact Report Table Format
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Enable compact report table format.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
A compact report table format was introduced in the Quartus II software version 5.1. If the Compact report table format option is turned on, the Quartus II Compiler produces Text-Format Report File (.rpt) files using a more readable format. The format displays tables in a vertical form instead of generating very wide lines. This format allows you to more easily browse the report file using a normal text editor (scrolling down instead of right). This option is turned off by default.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/global.chm::/global/gl_tab_processing.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To enable the compact report table format, open the Options dialog box on the Tools menu and click Processing under the General page. Then turn on Compact report table format.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	OPTIONS_PROCESS
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S2
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Additional report file options
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can generate HTML-format report files and a single combined report file after processing.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can generate an HTML format report file which can be viewed in an HTML browser. You can create a single combined text report Text-Format Report File (.rpt) with results from all parts of the compilation so that you can easily look at the full report in a text editor. These options are turned off by default.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/global.chm::/global/gl_tab_processing.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To set additional report output options, open the Options dialog box on the Tools menu and click Processing under the General page.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	OPTIONS_PROCESS
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S3
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Run Process at Lower Priority
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Run design processing at a lower priority (recommended for single processor machines).
</recommendation_description>
<description>
This option allows the Quartus II software to run a design process, such as a compilation or simulation, at a lower priority so that the Quartus II software does not consume all of the processor resources while it is processing a design. This option allows other applications to function better while the Quartus II software processes a design. Altera recommends this option for single processor computers. This option is turned off by default.
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To change the option to run design processing at a lower priority, open the Options dialog box on the Tools menu and click Processing under the General page. Then turn on Run design processing at a lower priority.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	OPTIONS_PROCESS
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="3">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S4
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
MAX+PLUS II Look and Feel
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can customize the Quartus II software to have the MAX+PLUS II software look and feel.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can change the look and feel of the Quartus II software by selecting either the Quartus II or MAX+PLUS II look and feel in the Customize dialog box on the Tools menu. The MAX+PLUS II look and feel allows you to use familiar MAX+PLUS II commands, icons, and layout to control functions of the Quartus II software.
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To select the MAX+PLUS II look and feel, open the Customize dialog box on the Tools menu and click the General page.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	CUSTOMIZE_DLG
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="4">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S5
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Add Tcl commands to toolbar buttons
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can define tcl commands and add them to toolbar buttons.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
On the Tcl tab in the Customize dialog box, you can configure ten buttons with Tcl commands and arguments to perform common Tcl actions.
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To add Tcl commands to toolbar buttons, open the Customize dialog box on the Tools menu and click the Tcl tab.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	CUSTOMIZE_DLG
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="5">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S6
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Update assignments to disk immediately
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can write the assignment changes immediately to a file after making a change in the GUI.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
By default, the Quartus II software saves assignment changes to a file only when you run a process. This default option improves the performance of the user interface especially when you are working with files across a network. If you wish to see changes saved to the Quartus II settings file (.qsf) immediately, you can turn this option off. This option is turned on by default.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/global.chm::/global/gl_tab_processing.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To have Quartus II software save assignments to a file immediately, open the Options dialog box on the Tools menu, and click Processing under the General page. Then turn off Update assignments to disk during design processing only.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	OPTIONS_PROCESS
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="6">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S7
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Suppress Messages
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can suppress messages in the Message window.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
If you find that the Quartus II software generates too many messages during processing, you may want to suppress some of the messages. Open the Options dialog box on the Tools menu, and then under Messages, click Suppression. You can suppress messages by type, such as information messages, by turning suppression on for those messages. In the Message window itself you can right-click on a message and suppress either the exact message or similar messages with the Suppress command. You can also open the Message Suppression Manager dialog box from this menu to review the suppressed message rules.
</description>
<more_info_link>
report.chm::/msw/msw_pro_view_mess.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To suppress messages by type, open the Options dialog box on the Tools menu and click Suppression under the Messages tab. You can also suppress exact or similar messages by right-clicking in the Message Window and clicking Suppress Exact Selected Messages or Suppress All Similar Messages.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	OPTIONS_MESSAGES_SUPRESSION
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="7">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S8
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Color messages during command-line compilation
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Display messages in color when using the command line.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can display system and processing messages in color when using the command line. Info messages display in green, Warning messages in blue, and Error messages in red.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/report.chm::/msw/msw_tab_message_tab_options.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To turn on the option to color messages during command-line compilation, open the Options dialog box on the Tools menu and click Messages.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	OPTIONS_MESSAGES
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="8">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S9
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use an External Text Editor
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can use an external text editor instead of the default text editor supplied with the Quartus II software.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can use your favorite text editor as the default when opening text files in the Quartus II software. You supply the location of the text editor executable and the command-line options and the Quartus II software uses that text editor whenever you open or locate to a text file.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/design.chm::/ted/ted_tab_text_editor.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To set your preferred text editor, open the Options dialog box on the Tools menu and click Text Editor, select Other text editor path name and supply the location of the text editor executable and the command-line options.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	OPTIONS_TEXT_EDITOR
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="9">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
S10
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Change the Tooltip Delay
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can specify how quickly and how long tooltips are displayed for certain tools in the Quartus II software.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can specify the number of seconds (0 to unlimited) that a tooltip persists while you place the mouse pointer over an object. You can also specify the number of seconds (0 to unlimited) you must hold the mouse pointer over an object before the tooltip displays.
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	You can independently set the options for tooltip persistence (Show names in tooltip for:) and for the delay before showing a tooltip (Delay showing tooltip for:) for several tools in the Quartus II software. Open the Options dialog box on theTools menu and click on the page for the tool to specify these settings.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	OPTIONS
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="10">
	SOFTWARE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
PROJECT
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Project Settings
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Project settings determine how your currently opened revision is processed.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
NA
</description>
<more_info_link>
NA
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	NA
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	NA
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="4">
	NONE
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
NA
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
P1
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Enable Version-Compatible Database
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can automatically export and import a version-compatible database as part of every compilation.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Prior to the Quartus II software version 4.1, compilation databases were locked to the current version of the Quartus II software. With the introduction of the Version-Compatible Database feature in the Quartus II software version 4.1, you can export a version-compatible database and import it into a later version. For example, using one set of design files, you can export a database generated from the Quartus II software version 4.1 and import it into the Quartus II software version 5.1 without recompiling your design. This feature can eliminate unnecessary compilation time.
</description>
<more_info_link>
http://www.altera.com/literature/hb/qts/qts_qii52012.pdf
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Enable exporting and importing a version-compatible database as part of every compilation. This feature exports to and imports from the "export_db" directory in your current project directory by default. To change this setting, open the Settings dialog box on the Assignments menu and click Compilation Process Settings.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_COMPILATION
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="1">
	PROJECT
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
P2
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Hide Entity Name
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can hide the entity name for node names.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
Hiding the entity name shortens the hierarchy path for node names. The entity name is displayed by default.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/comp.chm::/comp/comp_tab_mode.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	Disable entity name for node names. To turn this setting off, open the Settings dialog box on the Assignments menu and click Compilation Process Settings.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_COMPILATION
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="2">
	PROJECT
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
P3
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Specify the output directory for compilation results
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can save project output files in specified directory.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can specify a directory where the Quartus II software places all of the output files. The output files are placed in the project directory by default. 
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/comp.chm::/comp/comp_tab_mode.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To set the directory for compilation results, open the Settings dialog box on the Assignments menu and click Compilation Process Settings.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_COMPILATION
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="3">
	PROJECT
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
P4
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Specify what is done during a normal compilation
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
You can choose which optional processes are run when you start a normal compilation.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can run an I/O assignment analysis before compilation to quickly ensure that all of your I/O assignments are correct before starting a full fit.  This setting is off by default. You can choose not to run the Assembler as part of the compilation if you do not wish to create a programming file. This setting is on by default. You can choose to run RTL View preprocessing during compilation so that the RTL Viewer opens quickly after a compilation. This setting is off by default. 
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/comp.chm::/comp/comp_tab_mode.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To change these settings, open the Settings dialog box on the Assignments menu and click Compilation Process Settings.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_COMPILATION
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="4">
	PROJECT
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
P5
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Choose how the Fitter will process your design
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
There are several settings that can be used to change how the Fitter processes your design.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can direct the Fitter how to place logic elements in a device to meet your timing requirements. You can direct the Fitter to perform optimizations targeted at reducing the total power consumed by supported device families. You can specify the level of effort you want the Fitter to use to get a fit and specify whether it should only try to fit one time. 
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/comp.chm::/comp/comp_tab_fitting.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To change these settings, open the Settings dialog box on the Assignments menu and click Fitter Settings.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_FITTER
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="7">
	PROJECT
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
P6
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use Physical Synthesis to improve performance
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
The Quartus II software provides physical synthesis optimizations (for combinational logic and registers) to optimize the netlist during compilation.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
The physical synthesis optimizations are performed by Analysis &amp; Synthesis and the Fitter. Physical synthesis optimizations make placement-specific changes to the netlist that improve speed performance results for a specific Altera device.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/comp.chm::/comp/comp_tab_physical.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To turn on Physical synthesis for combinational logic or Physical synthesis for registers open the Settings dialog box on the Assignments menu and click Physical Synthesis Optimizations under Compilation Process Settings.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_PHYSICAL_SYNTHESIS
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="8">
	PROJECT
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
P7
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use Synthesis Netlist Optimizations to improve performance
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Use WYSIWYG primitive resynthesis or gate-level register retiming to optimize the design netlist during synthesis.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
These synthesis netlist optimizations occur during the synthesis stage of the compilation. Operating on the output from either an EDA synthesis tool or Quartus II Integrated Synthesis, these optimizations make changes to the synthesis netlist that improve either area or speed, depending on your selected optimization technique. WYSIWYG primitive resynthesis unmaps the logic elements in an atom netlist to gates and remaps the gates back to Altera LCELL primitives, with the logic optimization technique (achieving maximum speed performance or achieving minimum area) you specified in the Optimization Technique logic option. Gate-level register retiming allows registers to be moved across combinational logic to balance timing, but does not change the functionality of the current design.
</description>
<more_info_link>
quartus.chm::/comp.chm::/comp.chm::/comp/comp_tab_synthesis_fitting.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To turn on Perform WYSIWYG primitive resynthesis and/or Perform gate-level register retiming, open the Settings dialog box on the Assignments menu and click Synthesis Netlist Optimizations under Analysis &amp; Synthesis Settings.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_ANALYSIS_SYNTHESIS
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="9">
	PROJECT
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>

<optimization_record>
<recommendation_key>
P8
</recommendation_key>
<recommendation>
Use the Design Assistant to check for errors
</recommendation>
<recommendation_description>
Run the Design Assistant as part of the compilation to make sure there are no design issues that may affect the timing of your design.
</recommendation_description>
<description>
You can use the Design Assistant to check the reliability of a design based on a set of design rules. The Design Assistant can analyze and generate messages for a design that targets any Altera device supported by the Quartus II software.
</description>
<more_info_link>
verify.chm::/da/comp_view_doctor.htm
</more_info_link>
<effect_list>
	<fmax_effect>
	99
	</fmax_effect>
	<resource_effect>
	99
	</resource_effect>
	<compilation_effect>
	99
	</compilation_effect>
</effect_list>
<action>
	<action_description>
	To turn on the Design Assistant, open the Settings dialog box on the Assignments menu and click Design Assistant.
	</action_description>
	<action_link>
	SETD_DESIGN_ASSISTANT
	</action_link>
	<acf_variable_list>
		<acf_variable name="NA">
		
		</acf_variable>
	</acf_variable_list>
</action>
<device_family_list>
	<device_family exclude="">
	ALL
	</device_family>
</device_family_list>
<conditions>
</conditions>
<image_path>
1
</image_path>
<parent_list>
	<parent priority="10">
	PROJECT
	</parent>
</parent_list>
<logic_algorithm>
ALWAYS
</logic_algorithm>
<tcl_script button_name="" quartus_exe="">

</tcl_script>
</optimization_record>
</optimization_record_list>
